7th of March, 1892.
Juanito, my love.
This should not have happened.
Just wait...
We will see each other again.
I'm Carmela Isabella.
Soon-to-be twenty. Business
Management student.
Cool, right?
But no. I don't
like any of this.
And there must
be actions instead.
What the hell?
What is happening there?
And where are you
going, Ms. Isabella?
Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
Student Affairs Office.
I thought you and Shae
are no longer friends?
And also,
Mrs. Falcon called me earlier.
She said you and Shae interrupted
your Philippine History class.
Carmela...
why can't you be
like your cousins?
Look at them!
They're already all successful!
You're left behind!
I wish you were here, mom.
Carmela.
Carmela, why did Grandma
look at you that way?
Oh my God, Grandma.
I didn't know there's a
place like this in this mansion.
I want you to meet someone.
Okay... I'll admit.
Grandma's smile was a bit creepy.
But with all
the expensive things in here,
I wonder how much
I can sell them for.
She was the youngest
sister of Josefina,
who became a nun...
And Maria Montecarlos...
my grandmother.
So you mean to say,
our family came
from Maria Montecarlos...
I look so much like Carmelita.
Even though she was not
my great-great-grandmother.
It's simple enough.
She was also our ancestor.
Blood of our blood.
Flesh of our flesh.
I studied Genetics in high school.
Yes, we're related.
We share DNA and genes.
But is that really it?
We look like the same person!
She died the same age you are now.
What?
Grandma, what happened to her?
She was too blinded by love.
That was the reason for
all that happened to her.
One hundred and thirty two years.
Destiny had been waiting...
For this to happen.
Are you ready to find out...
the story behind the painting?
Grandma, isn't it better to include
Jenny and Emily as well?
They also love
hearing stories, you know.
It is not allowed.
No one may ever know about this.
Except the eldest
daughters in our family.
Carmelita lived
a quiet and peaceful life.
Together with her family…
They were the wealthiest in San Alfonso.
She was arranged to marry
Juanito by her parents.
The son of the Governorcillo.
The Alfonsos were
the most influential family…
Governing the town of San Alfonso.
Juanito and Carmelita fell
in love with each other.
So, the engagement
did not cause any problem.
But everything changed when
Juanito was murdered.
On the day of their wedding.
No one knew why he was killed.
And after just one week…
Carmelita took her own life.
She drowned herself in the lake.
That was very tragic, Grandma.
Like Romeo and Juliet.
When my grandmother told me
about the tragedy
that befell her sister…
We were here in this very room.
In front of that painting.
And when I saw
you for the first time…
I thought you were Carmelita.
But I know, it wasn't just
coincidence that you look alike.
Because you two
were born on the same day.
She was born on February 29, 1872.
Oh my God!
Grandma, my birthday
is February 29, 2004!
This was Carmelita's diary.
Read it.
So you might understand
their story better.
It was Maria Montecarlos' will
to name every eldest daughter
in our family after Carmelita.
She gave that diary
to her daughter,
Carmen, who was my mother.
She named me Carmina.
And I named my
own daughter, Carmenia.
And you were named Carmela.
But none of us were born during
the day that only happens every four years.
So that's why Carmela is my name.
I'm so girly but my name
sounds like an old maid.
Our love will be rewritten on
the day of the fourth chance.
Nosebleed.
Nevermind.
"I missed you?"
You two are together anyway.
God, I want to slam
their heads so bad!
But you know, since I'm nice,
I'm gonna leave a like.
No way!
They're having fun while I'm stuck
in this old house full of weird stories
and sulking inside a dead girl's
bedroom, who looks just like me.
No! I won't allow this!
It's time to party!
- There! Just one more!
- Alright…
Just one more left!
Do it! It's sure win!
- That's it! One more!
- Here I go!
Yes! Scatter! Scatter, babe!
Scatter! Look!
Hey, that's Playtime!
Go on, press it!
Maybe you're lucky.
Boom! Winner!
Thank you, miss.
Alright…
- Hi, ma'am.
- Hi, sir. Do you have vodka?
Sorry, ma'am. We don't have it.
How about a margarita?
- Thank you.
- Alright.
Sir, one margarita.
Shae needs to know
that I'm having fun too
and my weekend's not boring.
Hi, ma'am. Here's your order.
Thank you.
- I told her.
- Oh, wow. You really told her that?
Yeah, that's why.
Her makeup doesn't look good.
That girl's makeup looks wrong.
Yeah, I want to fix it for her actually.
Want me to tell her?
No need.
She might be offended.
Don't you worry. I'm here.
I will protect you.
- Wow...
- Rawr.
Oh, wow.
How's that again?
Carms, midterm results are posted!
Yes! I got 1.5!
2023-01892.
That's me. 2.75. Shit.
You?
Let's go celebrate. Eat out?
Let's go.
- Fishball?
- Sure. Is that what you want?
Yeah.
Dad…
Can I talk to you?
Oh. Yes, Carmela.
What do you wanna talk about?
It's about my course, actually.
Business Management is not for me.
Okay.
So, what course would
you like to take instead?
I don't know.
I want to find myself first.
Find out what I really want.
Carmela...
Isn't it too late for that?
I mean...
Your cousins have
already achieved a lot.
They're making names for themselves.
Considering you're all the same age.
You are falling behind.
Why do you always
compare me with my cousins?
We're different from each other.
Isn't it enough that I tried
to do what you wanted?
I'm sorry, Carmela.
I just don't want you to
give up so quickly and easily.
It's not even about giving up.
What if my passion is in the arts?
Carmela...
it's hard to build
a future in the arts.
Of course, it's better
to choose a path in which you'll
have a better and stable future.
And that's business.
Dad... I'm not
interested in business.
Carmela...
Listen to me.
After you graduate,
I will retire early.
I will help you put up
your own business.
And then, I'll have more time
for you and your sisters.
You want that, right?
Good girl.
You can do it.
Can you still handle it, Carmela?
He's my classmate.
James!
What kind of pass is that?
Sorry.
Were you hurt?
It's okay. I was just startled.
Don't be sad.
You'll get through it.
You can do it. Just smile.
There.
You're prettier when you smile.
What are we doing here?
You don't even like basketball.
We're gonna watch my crush play.
- Crush?
- Mm-hmm.
It's him again!
He's so handsome.
Shit, he smiled at me!
What? Who?
My crush!
Number eight. James!
Go, James! Do your best!
Wow!
Thank you, Lord. I made it.
I can't be late on
the first day of the semester.
Oh, Carmela. Sit over here.
- Let's sit together.
- Alright.
- Traffic?
- Yeah.
So handsome! Lucky,
I'm sitting beside him.
It's okay. At least
we're in the same class.
Hi.
Shae helped me out earlier.
Hey, why did you tell her?
It's fine. It's just Carmela.
Remember, we talked
about something?
What did you talk about?
Secret.
Don't tell her, okay?
Why do I feel like
I'm being left out?
Are you sure?
Carmela, let's go.
We'll be late to the party.
- Let's go. Come with us.
- Yeah.
I...
have an exam tomorrow.
I need to review, you know,
so... you guys enjoy.
- You sure?
- Mm-hmm.
Alright.
- Bye.
- Alright.
Carmela!
- Carmela, please!
- What is it?
Give it to me straight.
What's your problem?
You've been avoiding
hanging out with me and James.
I'm just busy.
You're lying.
I can see it in your eyes.
You know what?
Believe what you want to believe.
You're so full of shit!
For once, can't you just say
what's on your mind?
You really want to know
what I'm thinking?
I hate you.
Because you and James
are close to each other.
You're always talking,
always together.
It's breaking my heart.
Don't tell me you also like James?
What kind of friend are you?
I told you first
that he's my crush.
And now you're telling
me you like him too?
Shae... it's not that.
It's exactly that.
The thing about you...
you're too spoiled.
Too entitled.
Whatever you want, you get.
You don't care if
other people get hurt.
If that's what you think of me...
Then you don't
really know me, Shae.
You're not a real friend to me.
Maybe you're right.
But don't expect that
I will give James up for you.
Because no!
Never!
Carmela.
- I'm going to class.
- Wait.
I don't know what happened
between you and Shae.
Please. Don't avoid me too.
James, what's wrong
if I do avoid you?
You have tons of friends.
Your basketball team,
your fans...
Even Shae.
But you're different, Carmela.
And what makes me different, James?
Because I like you.
No... It's Shae you like.
No. It's you I want.
I'm just asking for her help
to get close to you.
I wanted to court you, but...
I felt scared...
That you will just outright reject me.
Please.
Believe me.
Carmela.
Carmela, please. Listen to me.
Carmela!
Please, keep your distance from James.
Seriously?
Shae... James confessed to me.
He said I'm the one he likes.
I don't care.
You can't steal him from me.
You have everything you want.
But me, I have no one, Carmela.
I only have James.
So, don't take him away.
Here you go.
James... I already told you
to stop bugging me.
And I also told you,
I won't be doing that.
I want you, Carmela.
James,
Shae has feelings for you, okay?
So, what?
Lots of other girls
have a crush on me.
Shae's not the only one.
Shae's my friend.
I don't want her to get hurt.
But... how about you?
Me?
I know you want me too, Carmela.
Is he serious right now?
Don't make it hard for yourself.
James! Will you please stop?
Shae?
What? Carmela is flirting
with James?
Isn't Shae and James
an item already?
Well, as Shae said so herself,
"looks can be deceiving."
Carmela's secretly a hoe.
Poor Shae. Her own
best friend betrayed her.
Whatever Shae is saying,
it's all lies.
I can prove it to everyone.
That was your fault...
That bitch!
She's really getting on my nerves!
She better watch out for me.
- Is she still there?
- She left already.
I haven't finished it yet.
You've been telling everyone
that I'm flirting with James, huh?
What do you mean?
I don't even have to do that.
The whole school can clearly
see what you've been doing.
I'm not doing anything wrong, Shae.
I'm trying so hard
to be considerate of you.
Considerate?
Didn't I tell you to keep
your distance from James?
But you didn't listen.
So if you've become
the talk of the town...
You just reap what you sow.
You want drama?
I'll give you a whole damn show.
Just keep this in mind...
I'm the type of person
you don't want as your enemy.
Great! You deserve each other!
No! You will not ruin my night.
Erase, erase, erase!
Sir!
You know...
Being by yourself is quite lonely.
But if you'd like...
I'm willing to keep you company.
Excuse me.
The nerve...
He's not even handsome.
Weird...
Why am I getting dizzy?
I only had one Margarita.
Why can't I book a ride?
Isn't there any taxi here?
Hey...
It's too early to go home.
- No...
- Oh, come on.
- No, please go.
- Come on. Let's go.
- Ouch!
- Hey!
- I told you, no!
- Wait up...
Come on.
What the hell
are you doing, man?
Dad! Carmela's awake!
How are you feeling now?
My head hurts.
Why are we here?
You don't remember anything, Carmela?
The only thing I remember...
I was outside the bar.
Waiting for a ride home...
Then there's this stranger that
came up and talked to me...
Carmela Isabella!
Didn't you know you almost got into
trouble because of your stubbornness?
Dad...
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean it to happen.
And I'm sorry too.
Because from now on,
you may not leave the house
unless you're going to school.
But how about
my birthday celebration, Dad?
Don't you know what you did
was awfully dangerous?
I don't know what I would do
if ever you got hurt!
And if I need to be strict, I will.
Just to make sure it won't happen again.
I'm sorry.
Your birthday party is cancelled.
Dad! No!
That's alright, Carmela.
Good thing there
was a guy who saved you.
If not...
then maybe something
worse could have happened.
What do you mean?
When the police called,
they told us you were
at the station, unconscious.
A guy took you there.
Together with the other guy
who wanted to rape you.
Good thing you have
IDs on your wallet.
They saw Dad's calling card in there.
And then, when
we arrived at the station...
The suspect was already in jail.
They say it was that Paulo's modus
to put sleeping powder
into the drinks of his victims.
Carmela, good thing
somebody saw you.
But still, Dad already decided
to come back to Manila later.
Just in case, that Paulo
can pay his bail.
He might follow you again.
But wait, where was
the guy who helped me?
We didn't see him.
Oh! But...
He left his name and
number with the police.
Carmela, what's this?
Are you collecting old stuff now?
Grandma Carmina owns this.
Hey, girls. Our oral presentation
would be later, right?
- That's right.
- Are you ready?
We have to do our best.
I'll handle our slideshow, okay?
By the way, Carmela.
Those related articles about
the well-known families.
Where is it again?
I'll look for it.
Okay, I'll leave it to you.
We're heading back.
Let's go.
Happy birthday!
Here we go again.
Why won't this guy
stop bothering me?
Can't he see I want to live
a peaceful life now?
You're so grumpy.
I just miss you. That's it.
Are you free later?
Let's have some dinner.
Same place like before.
James, I have things to do later.
Besides, you have Shae.
Just take her to dinner.
Shae again?
But today's not her birthday, right?
It's yours.
Wait... Is that Carmelita's diary?
So? Are you game later?
I'll just be waiting for you.
I have to go. Bye.
This is not your diary.
And it will never be yours.
Sister!
What the hell?
Are you doing this on purpose?
Shae, not now. I'm in a hurry.
So, what? You're gonna
avoid me again?
You're good at that.
You never say sorry.
Spoiled brat!
Bitch!
How I wish I was really
insensitive and selfish, Shae.
So that I wouldn't have to give up
my feelings for James.
Since you ended our friendship anyway.
Sister!
Please... give me back my dairy.
You cannot have this, dear.
It belongs to someone else.
My grandma owns that.
She'll get upset if I lost it.
Don't you worry.
She won't get mad.
Sister!
Aren't you getting tired?
Please stop!
If not for this nun's age,
I would've tackled her.
She should be grateful
I'm still being respectful.
Sister!
My god...
Stop! I'm not allowed to go through there!
I won't be able to graduate!
Your love will be rewritten
on the day of the fourth chance.
Huh?
And today is that fateful day.
I'll just pick it up,
I won't pass through.
Huh?
How did you--
You were just there moments ago.
Yes.
But I won't leave without you.
What happened to you?
Are you hurt?
Miss?
Carmelita?
How are you feeling?
Where am I?
What is this place?
You have to bring me back
to the place where you found me!
I want to go back home!
She is not Carmelita!
You!
What's wrong with all of you?
There is no other way
back to your own time...
Unless you finish your mission here.
Miss!
Whatever happens...
Don't you dare
fall in love with me.
Carmela, dear... Don't you forget...
That you are Carmelita
while you are here.
Mind your actions.
Refrain from being unrefined.
- Don Mariano!
- We arrived too early.
Beside him is his wife.